https://www.helpsystems.com/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
Privacy Policy
Last Updated: August 12, 2020
HelpSystems is committed to protecting your privacy. This Statement of Privacy applies to any and all HelpSystems brands and affiliated sites. This statement governs the data collection, processing, and usage practices of HelpSystems. By using the HelpSystems website, you consent to the data practices described in this Statement. This Statement of Privacy applies to information acquired on the website only and not to information acquired elsewhere.
Website Collection and Use Practices
HelpSystems collects personally identifiable information provided by users when they submit a web form on one of our websites. This information includes non-sensitive data such as your email address, name, company name, home and/or work address and/or telephone number.
In the event that you contact us through the website, we may also request that you provide additional user information relevant to the support you request. Users are under no obligation to provide such information. However, we cannot guarantee that we can provide customer support in the event that relevant information related to the use of our products or services is withheld. We may retain communications relating to customer support, and/or information drawn from such communications, for statistical and/or reference purposes.
Social Media (Features) and Widgets
Our website(s) includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, “Share This” button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
Links to Other Websites
Our site includes links to other website(s) whose privacy practices may differ from those of HelpSystems. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website(s) you visit.
Testimonials
With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.
Public Forums and Comment Sections
Our website(s) offers publicly accessible message boards, blogs, and community forums. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through HelpSystems public message boards, blogs, or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: HelpSystems does not share your private online communications with others.
Use of Personal Information: Opt Out and Unsubscribe
HelpSystems has a legitimate interest in collecting and using your personal information for the reasons set forth in this section.  HelpSystems collects and uses your personal information to operate the HelpSystems website and deliver the services you have requested.  In addition, HelpSystems collects and uses your personal information in order to process requests submitted by website users and to support communication with customers or those with contractual obligations. HelpSystems may also use your personally identifiable information for sales and marketing purposes related to other HelpSystems products or services. You can withdraw your consent at any time but withdrawing your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any communications HelpSystems has sent to you before your consent was withdrawn. HelpSystems may also collect your personal information via voluntary surveys or contests in order to conduct market research or to collect feedback in order to improve our products and services. You will always have the option to unsubscribe (see “To Unsubscribe From HelpSystems” below). HelpSystems does not sell, rent, or lease its customer lists to third parties in which we do not have a formal agreement to provide services to HelpSystems and our customers or prospects. HelpSystems does not share personally identifiable information except as described in this policy.
HelpSystems may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (email, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, HelpSystems may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries or contact you based on your interest to receive such communications. Such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to HelpSystems, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. HelpSystems does not collect sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.
HelpSystems also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites using log files.  We may use and share aggregate or non-personal information without restriction. If you access this website from outside the U.S., you acknowledge, agree, and consent that any information you provide, including any personal information, will be transferred to and processed by a computer server located within the U.S.
There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by HelpSystems. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information is used by HelpSystems for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the HelpSystems website. For these purposes, we do link this automatically collected data to personally identifiable information such as name, email address, address, and phone number.
Third-Party Services
HelpSystems uses a variety of third-party services, including Google Analytics, Omniconvert and Hotjar. These services may automatically collect information provided by your browser as part of a web page request, such as your referring domain, cookies, or your IP address. HelpSystems also uses Gong, a service that enables it to record, transcribe, analyze and share the contents of its sales communications, including phone calls, video conferences, email and other correspondences, as well as its CRM and customer contacts. For more information on how these tools collect and use your information, please refer to their respective privacy policies. By using our website, you consent to the processing of data by these third parties in accordance with their privacy policies.
Third-Party Tracking Technologies
The use of cookies and web beacons by any tracking utility company is covered in our Cookie Policy.
Do Not Track Disclosure
This website does not monitor for or behave differently if your computer transmits a “do not track” or similar beacon or message.
Legal Disclaimer
HelpSystems websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary or reasonably desirable in our business judgment to protect our interests or those of third parties to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on HelpSystems or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of HelpSystems (including enforcing this agreement); and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of HelpSystems, or the public.
Access to Personally Identifiable Information
You have the following rights with respect to your personal information:
To review the user information that you have supplied to us
To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions in user information that you have supplied to us
To request that your user information not be used to contact you
To request that your user information be removed from any solicitation list that we use
To request that your user information be removed from our records and
To unsubscribe
GDPR
HelpSystems complies with the GDPR. If you wish to submit a personal data request related to the GDPR, please complete this form.
CCPA
HelpSystems complies with the CCPA. If you wish to submit a personal data request related to the CCPA, please complete this form.
We will respond to all requests within 30 days. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Security of your Personal Information
No method of safeguarding information is 100% secure. HelpSystems uses a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. HelpSystems secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. HelpSystems may use third-party SSL-secured payment processors to collect credit card data.
Data Retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If the data is no longer needed and there is no legal requirement to maintain the personal data indefinitely, your data may be maintained for up to 12 months. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at info@helpsystems.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Changes to this Statement
HelpSystems will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy. HelpSystems encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how HelpSystems is protecting your information. When such a change is made, we will update the “Last Updated” date above. If we make any material changes we will notify you or our Client by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
To Unsubscribe from HelpSystems
You may unsubscribe from HelpSystems communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of your email or emailing us at info@helpsystems.com. Current customers or those with contractual obligations will continue to receive product updates and other important communications.
Contact Information
HelpSystems welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that HelpSystems has not adhered to this Statement, please contact HelpSystems at info@helpsystems.com. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem. If HelpSystems cannot resolve a complaint to your satisfaction you can contact the ICO at www.ico.org.uk or by telephoning 0303 123 1113 if the complaint relates to the way your personal data has been handled.
HelpSystems is located at 6455 City West Parkway, Eden Prairie, MN 55344. We can be reached by phone at 800-328-1000.
Visuals and Photography
HelpSystems owns the rights to all visual content on www.helpsystems.com including all logos, photographs, icons, infographics, graphics, and any other imagery. Most of the photography used on our website was shot on-site at Atmosphere Commercial Interiors and Foresight Associates in Minneapolis, MN.
Copyright Terms and Conditions
The content on this website is protected by the Copyright Laws of the United States of America and other countries worldwide. The unauthorized use and/or duplication of this material without express and written permission from HelpSystems is strictly prohibited. Excerpts and links may be used, provided that full and clear credit is given to HelpSystems with appropriate and specific direction to the original content.
